A Finding Aid to the Frank Perls Papers and Frank Perls Gallery Records, circa 1920-1983, bulk 1949-1975, in the Archives of American Art AAA.perlfran
Archives of American Art
- Subject Files, circa 1939-1983; Series 4; (Box 6-22; 16.5 linear feet)
  - Richard J. Rasmussen, 1951-1971 (Box 19, Folder 31)
  - Olie Rauh, 1955-1958 (Box 19, Folder 32)
  - Vladimir Raykis, 1953-1965 (Box 19, Folder 33)
  - James Real, 1973 (Box 19, Folder 34)
  - Reed College, 1963-1964 (Box 19, Folder 35)
  - Pierre-Auguste Renoir, 1970-1971 (Box 19, Folder 36)
  - John Rewald, 1951-1974; (3 folders) (Box 19, Folder 37-39)
  - Robert Rifkind, 1955, 1969-1974; (3 folders) (Box 19, Folder 40-42)
  - Robert Rifkind - Litigation Against Frank Perls' Estate, 1975 (Box 19, Folder 43)
  - Edward G. Robinson, 1956-1971 (Box 20, Folder 1)
  - Edward G. Robinson - Art Collection, 1955-1956 (Box 20, Folder 2)
  - Allan Roos, 1962-1964, 1972-1973 (Box 20, Folder 3)
  - Bernard Rosenthal, 1951-1955, 1973 (Box 20, Folder 4)
  - Georges Rouault, circa 1958-1960 (Box 20, Folder 5)
  - Henri Rousseau, Undated (Box 20, Folder 6)
  - Peter Paul Rubens, Undated (Box 20, Folder 7)
  - Madeleine Russell, 1950-1971 (Box 20, Folder 8)
  - Niki de Saint Phalle, 1968-1969 (Box 20, Folder 9)
  - Miscellaneous Sa, 1950-1975 (Box 20, Folder 10)
  - Miscellaneous Sc, 1950-1975 (Box 20, Folder 11)
  - Miscellaneous Se, 1950-1975 (Box 20, Folder 12)
  - Miscellaneous Sh, 1950-1975 (Box 20, Folder 13)
  - Miscellaneous Si, 1950-1975 (Box 20, Folder 14)
  - Miscellaneous Sl-Sp, 1950-1975 (Box 20, Folder 15)
  - Miscellaneous Sta, 1950-1975 (Box 20, Folder 16)
  - Miscellaneous Ste, 1950-1975 (Box 20, Folder 17)
  - Miscellaneous Sto-Stu, 1950-1975 (Box 20, Folder 18)
  - Miscellaneous Su-Sy, 1950-1975 (Box 20, Folder 19)
  - Saidenberg Gallery, 1953-1974 (Box 20, Folder 20)
  - Samuel Kootz Gallery, 1949-1954 (Box 20, Folder 21)
  - San Francisco Museum of Art, 1950-1971; (2 folders) (Box 20, Folder 22-23)
  - San Felipe Gallery, 1953-1955 (Box 20, Folder 24)
  - Santa Barbara Museum of Art, 1950-1974; (4 folders) (Box 20, Folder 25-28)
  - William Saroyan, 1942, 1954 (Box 20, Folder 29)
  - William Schonfeldt, 1972-1974 (Box 20, Folder 30)
  - Taft Schreiber, 1965-1968 (Box 20, Folder 31)
  - Hans de Schulthess Estate, 1963-1967 (Box 20, Folder 32)
  - Kurt Schweidler, 1969-1974 (Box 20, Folder 33)
  - Franz Seeman, 1950-1951 (Box 20, Folder 34)
  - Andre Dunoyer de Segonzac, 1962 (Box 20, Folder 35)
  - Jacques Seligmann and Company, 1953-1959 (Box 20, Folder 36)
  - Jennifer Jones Selznick, 1946, 1970-1971 (Box 20, Folder 37)
  - Richard Sherwood, 1962-1969 (Box 20, Folder 38)
  - Sydney Shoenberg, 1954-1956 (Box 20, Folder 39)
  - Sidney Sheldon, 1971-1972 (Box 20, Folder 40)
  - Harry Sherwood, 1956-1959 (Box 20, Folder 41)
  - Sidney Janis Gallery, 1951-1961 (Box 20, Folder 42)
  - Lucille Ellis Simon, 1970-1971 (Box 20, Folder 43)
  - Norton Simon, 1962, 1967-1973; (2 folders) (Box 21, Folder 1-2)
  - Noel Singer, 1964 (Box 21, Folder 3)
  - George Slaff, 1951-1969 (Box 21, Folder 4)
  - Marvin Small, 1959-1974 (Box 21, Folder 5)
  - Caroline Snyder, 1950-1974 (Box 21, Folder 6)
  - The Solomon R. Guggenheim Museum, 1953-1975 (Box 21, Folder 7)
  - Sotheby and Company, 1966-1975; (3 folders) (Box 21, Folder 8-10)
  - Chaim Soutine, 1973 (Box 21, Folder 11)
  - The Stable Gallery, 1955-1956 (Box 21, Folder 12)
  - Otto Stangl, 1953-1968; (2 folders) (Box 21, Folder 13-14)
  - Stephen Hahn Gallery, 1957-1974 (Box 21, Folder 15)
  - Ray Stark, 1950-1973 (Box 21, Folder 16)
  - Gertrude Stein Estate, 1967 (Box 21, Folder 17)
  - Lionel Steinberg, 1950-1954, 1970 (Box 21, Folder 18)
  - Saul Steinberg, 1950-1967 (Box 21, Folder 19)
  - Frederick Stern - Deposition Regarding Authenticity of Painting by Rembrandt, 1973 (Box 21, Folder 20)
  - Ala Story, 1959-1972 (Box 21, Folder 21)
  - Barbra Streisand, 1971-1972 (Box 21, Folder 22)
  - James Strombotne, 1957-1965, 1974; (6 folders) (Box 21, Folder 23-28)
  - David Stuart, 1969 (Box 21, Folder 29)
  - Paul Suttman, 1970-1973 (Box 21, Folder 30)
  - Miscellaneous T, 1950-1975 (Box 21, Folder 31)
  - Tamarind Lithography Workshop, 1962-1965 (Box 21, Folder 32)
  - Rufino Tamayo, 1951-1978 (Box 21, Folder 33)
  - Ann Taniguchi, 1953-1954 (Box 21, Folder 34)
  - Lorenzo Tedesco, 1950-1954 (Box 21, Folder 35)
  - Richard Tetlie, 1966-1968 (Box 21, Folder 36)
  - Eugene Thaw, 1910-1975 (Box 21, Folder 37)
  - Travel to U.S.S.R., 1959 (Box 21, Folder 38)
  - Guenther Troche, 1954-1956, 1966 (Box 21, Folder 39)
  - Johanna Tuohy, 1964, 1970-1975 (Box 21, Folder 40)
  - Miscellaneous U (includes universities), 1950-1975 (Box 21, Folder 41)
  - United Production of America (UPA) - Raoul Dufy Film, 1955-1956 (Box 21, Folder 42)
  - United States Customs, 1956-1974 (Box 21, Folder 43)
  - University of California, 1950-1973; (2 folders) (Box 21, Folder 44-45)
  - University of California at Los Angeles Art Council, 1959-1970 (Box 21, Folder 46)
  - University of Illinois, 1952-1964 (Box 21, Folder 47)
  - University of Southern California, 1950-1954 (Box 21, Folder 48)
  - University of Washington - Henry Gallery, 1953-1956 (Box 21, Folder 49)
  - Miscellaneous V, 1950-1975 (Box 21, Folder 50)
  - Maurice Utrillo, circa 1959 (Box 22, Folder 1)
  - Curt Valentin, 1950-1956, 1984; (4 folders) (Box 22, Folder 2-5)
  - Elsabe Valcke, 1970-1972 (Box 22, Folder 6)
  - Vincent Van Gogh, circa 1958-1960 (Box 22, Folder 7)
  - Leonor Vassena, 1963 (Box 22, Folder 8)
  - Doris Vidor (Mrs. Charles), 1950-1967 (Box 22, Folder 9)
  - Virginia Museum of Fine Arts, 1958 (Box 22, Folder 10)
  - Maurice de Vlaminck, 1957 (Box 22, Folder 11)
  - Miscellaneous Wa, 1950-1975 (Box 22, Folder 12)
  - Miscellaneous We-Wh, 1950-1975 (Box 22, Folder 13)
  - Miscellaneous Wi-Wy, 1950-1975 (Box 22, Folder 14)
  - Hal B. Wallis, 1963-1975 (Box 22, Folder 15)
  - Howard Warshaw, 1950-1958; (3 folders) (Box 22, Folder 16-18)
  - Lew Wasserman, 1958-1970 (Box 22, Folder 19)
  - Frederick Weisman, 1963-1966 (Box 22, Folder 20)
  - The Westland School, 1958-1960 (Box 22, Folder 21)
  - The Weyhe Gallery, 1949-1954 (Box 22, Folder 22)
  - Whitney Museum of American Art, 1956-1971 (Box 22, Folder 23)
  - Billy Wilder, 1950-1975; (3 folders) (Box 22, Folder 24-26)
  - James Wilson, 1962 (Box 22, Folder 27)
  - Anne Windfohr (Tandy), 1951-1975; (3 folders) (Box 22, Folder 28-30)
  - Anne Windfohr (Tandy) - Inventory Sheets, circa 1962 (Box 22, Folder 31)
  - James Wines, 1958-1959 (Box 22, Folder 32)
  - George Wittenborn, 1954-1974 (Box 22, Folder 33)
  - Natalie Wood, 1969-1975 (Box 22, Folder 34)
  - Zao Wou-Ki, 1963-1969 (Box 22, Folder 35)
  - Paul Wunderlich, 1969-1973 (Box 22, Folder 36)
  - Miscellaneous Y, 1950-1975 (Box 22, Folder 37)
  - Audrey Young, 1950-1972 (Box 22, Folder 38)
  - Stanley Young, 1953-1954 (Box 22, Folder 39)
  - Miscellaneous Z, 1950-1975 (Box 22, Folder 40)
  - Charles Zakok, 1952-1956 (Box 22, Folder 41)
  - Paul Ziffren, 1954-1971 (Box 22, Folder 42)
  - Pauline Zollner (Soergel), 1970-1972 (Box 22, Folder 43)
- Scrapbooks, 1937-1957; Series 5; (Box 28; .3 linear feet)
  Two scrapbooks document the activities of the Perls Gallery in New York from 1937-1939 and the Frank Perls Gallery in Los Angeles from 1951-1957. The scrapbooks contain carefully dated newspaper and magazine clippings and exhibition announcements.
  - Oversized Scrapbook - Perls Gallery in New York, 1937-1939 (Box 28)
  - Oversized Scrapbook - Frank Perls Gallery in Los Angeles, 1951-1957; (2 folders) (Box 28)